Guide to the Warren Jay Vinton papers, 1932-1969
Vinton, Warren Jay papers, 1932-1969
- Series II. Chief Economist. Office Files [1935-1945]-1949
  - "President's Lists"-Summary Reports on the President's Defense List #7: Binder of project applicatoins approved by U.S.H.A., indexed, 1942 (Box 17)
  - "Quotations"-Identification of quotations, Feb. 27, 1943-Dec. 14, 1944 (Box 17)
  - "R-Miscellaneous"-correspondence, 1949 (Box 1)
  - "Racial Relations"-Reprints of articles by Robt. Weaver on racial policy in public housing 1938-1940; correspondence, orders, memoranda on housing of negro war workers in public housing; statements on race relations in housing policy by NPHC; pamphlets and legal briefs by Charles Abrams 1947; statement of NHA experience of 10 years in public housing, statement of race relations policy of public housing administration, from Frank Horne, FPHA Race Relations Office, 1938-Aug. 18, 1949 (Box 4)
  - ?Rent Certificates?-correspondence reports in binder, ca. 1942-April 30, 1948 (Box 4)
  - ?Rent and Tenancy Policies?-Inter-office memoranda, correspondence, drafts and completed revision of U.S.H.A. Bulletin 24 Income Limits and Rents for eligibility of tenants in U.S.H.A.-aided low-rental projects, also comparison with English rental projects; from Jacob Crane, David Krooth, Nathan Straus, Leon Keyserling, Edith Klmer Wood, consultant, June 29, 1939-May 20, 1940 (Box 3)
  - ?Rental Value of Owned Homes S and R?-Inter-office memoranda, statements, cost comparisons between U.S.H.A. an F.H.A. program on shelter rent and its relation to family, Feb. 10, 1940-April 5, 1941 (Box 3)
  - ?Rents and Income Limit?-pamphlet ?Adjusted Rents?, 1941 (Box 1)
  - ?Repairs, Maintenance and Replacement?-Reserves-Revision of 1948: Memos, correspondence, chart on revision of reserves set aside for repairs, report of Special Committee of PHA on Reserves for Low-Rent Housing Projects, revision of Low Housing Authority Manual, circular to Regional Directors minutes of meeting of NAHO and PHA officials, July 24, 1947-Sept. 30, 1948 (Box 4)
  - ?Repairs, Maintenance and Replacement, through 1949?-Correspondence, interoffice memos, charts, tables on policy on reserves and reductions in subsidy to PWA Housing Division projects, U.S.H.A. policy on what is to be included in repairs, maintenance and replacement, manual replacement on accounting procedure, measures to avoid increased operating expenses, reserves for vacancy and collection bases, Nov. 15, 1938-April 12, 1943 (Box 4)
  - ?Resettlement Administration?-Bankhead-Black Bill, Legislation History: Interoffice memoranda, copies of Senate and House bills, data for hearings, hearings before Subcommittee of Committee on Ways and Means, House of Reps. Amended bill, report, Congressional Record, copy of act; Administration concerned list provisions extend to projects of 1 govt. dept. but not all, Apr. 28, 1936-June 29, 1936 (Box 4)
  - ?Resettlement Administration?-Allocation of funds to resettlement administration: Memoranda on analysis of authorization for specific work projects, copy of allotment of funds to Resettlement Administration Sept. 23, 1935, memorandum from General Counsel of Resettlement Administration to division directors etc. on funds allocated to Branch, Sept. 23-Oct. 31, 1946 (Box 5)
  - ?Resettlement Administration?-Bankhead-Black Bill-Payment Lieu Taxes: Memoranda, draft of farms; on Bankhead Act (H.R. 12876) of June 29, 1936 authorizing Resettlement Administration to make payments in lieu of taxes, report on costs to be shared, contracts with states, draft of administrative order on procedure, July 8, 1936-Nov. 13, 1936 (Box 4)
  - ?Resettlement Administration?-Publications: Resettlement Administration public statement on its activities, program of Resettlement Admin., ?Our New National Domain? by Rexford Tugwell, March 1936; ?America?s Land? 1936 pamphlet of R.A.; ?What the Resettlement Administration Has Done,? ?Rural Resettlement? by Will Alexander; ?America?s Town Planning begins? article by Henry Churchill on Greenbelt towns, esp. Greenbrook, Nov. 20, 1935-Nov. 1936 (Box 5)
  - ?Resettlement Administration?-Rent Policy, R.A.: Memo by Tugwell on establishment of community organizations to handle transfer and sale of property from federal government, correspondence on reduction of interest rate, adjustment of rents according to income, Dec. 1935-April 8, 1937 (Box 5)
  - ?Resettlement Administration?-Resettlement: Correspondence, memoranda, order establishing Administration, reports on resettlement projects, costs of services, selection of projects, chronology of Boundbrook case, lists of projects and their evaluation, social facilities and management standards for public housing, Buck Hill conference 1935, recommendations of Committee on Resettlement Projects, 1945, [1933-1937], 1945 (Box 5)
  - ?Resettlement Administration?-Studies [Resettlement Administration]: Tabulations on Cincinnati, Greendale and Greenbelt questionnaires, analyses of questionnaire data from Greenhills, Ohio and Greenbelt, Md., and report on Cincinnati and selection of site for suburban resettlement submitted by Vinton as Chief of Research, Research Section, Division of Suburban Resettlement, Resettlement Administration, March 19, 1936-June 15, 1936 (Box 5)
  - ?Resettlement Administration?-Studies R.A.: Tabulation on questionnaire on Greenhills, Greendale, Greenbelt; analysis of questionnaire data on same; report on site selection in Cincinnati and Milwaukee; report on wage policy, Greenbelt; (TS) memo on disposal of Greenbelt towns, submitted by Vinton as Chief of Research section, Division of Suburban Resettlement, [March 19-June 15, 1936], 1945 (Box 5)
  - ?Resettlement Administration?-Studies, R.A.: 3 binders entitled ?Summary of Information? for Greenbelt, Greenbrook and Greendale respectively, with memo from Vinton; (TS) binder, indexed ?Greenbelt Towns, Study of Background and Planning of Four Communities.. .? by Henry Churchill for Loansill, director, n.d. (TS), 1936 (Box 24)
  - "Resettlement Administration"-Tugwell Speeches, R.A.: Speech at Los Angeles (MC); drafts (TS) and press release (MC) of speech at Cincinnati on Greenbelt Project; clipping Chicago Daily Tribune, Nov. 19, 1936 announcing Tugwell's resignation, Jan. 25, 1946-Nov. 19, 1936 (Box 3)
  - "Roadtown"-Outline, report, photo, 1935 (Box 1)
  - "Room Count"-Interoffice memoranda, policy, bulletins, correspondence concerning definitions and requirements for room count and sizes, May 25, 1938-Dec. 27, 1946 (Box 3)
  - "Rural Housing"-Correspondence, interoffice memoranda, forms, manuals, reports on U.S.H.A. rural low-rent housing program, questions of policy decisions, local administration through housing authorities, restriction of program through war and postwar pressure, proposed division of jurisdiction and distinction between rural farm and rural non-farm; Catherine Bauer, Edith E. Wood, also letters from Nathan Straus, Leon Keyserling, Leo B. Hamilton, June 29, 1939-July 6, 1948 (Box 2)
  - "Speeches-Blanford"-Speeches of John Blanford, Jr., Administrator of N.H. Agency (MC), 1943-1945 (Box 18)
  - "Speeches-General"-Speech by Charlies Eliot, National Resources Committee (MC), May 3, 1936 (Box 18)
  - "Speeches-Keyserling"-Speeches of Leon Keyserling, General Counsl, National Housing Agency (MC), 1943-1945 (Box 18)
  - "Speeches-Klutznick"-Speeches by Philip Klutznick, Commissioner of Federal Public Housing Authority (MC), 1944-1946 (Box 18)
  - "Speeches-Straus, Nathan"-Speeches by Nathan Straus, Administrator, U.S. Housing Authority, 1935-1941 (Box 18)
  - "Staff Meeting Minutes"-1938-1946"-Agenda for Commissioner's staff meeting, June 17, 1942-Jan. 19, 1943; Summary of Commissioner's meetings, April 21, 1938, January 20, 1943-Dec. 31, 1946; MC, unnumbered series, April 21, 1938-Dec. 31, 1946 (Box 3)
  - "Staff Meetings"-Minutes 1947-48-49 [blue tab] (Title varies: Commissioner's staff meeting, Jan.-July 1947; General Staff meeting Aug. 4, 1947; Executive staff meeting Aug. 12, 1947 concurrently numbered with title General Staff meeting) MC, Jan. 7, 1947-Oct. 24, 1949 (Box 3)
  - [Straus, Nathan. Designation] (not original folder but file maintained-Letters from Judge Sam Rosenman concerning reorganization of housing agency; notes of Vinton's criticism of Straus and necessity for his resignation; MC letter of resignation from Straus, Jan. 5, 1942; TS annotated copy of Strus' announcement of resignation, Oct. 22, 1942; Oct. 12, 1941-Oct. 22, 1942 (Box 1)
  - "Stein, Clarence S."-Memoranda, correspondence to and from Stein regarding his preparation of budget for operating and maintenance costs of Greenbelt towns; see also Greenbelt and Suburban Resettlement, 1933-1935 (Box 24)
  - "Subsistence Homesteads"-TS copy of confidential report "A History of Subsistence Homesteads Division" by Bruce Melvin, sociologist, and Ernistine Evans, Dec. 17, 1936; MC transcript marked "Confidential" of discussion at Conference on Subsistence Homesteads in their Relationship to Social Plannin, Brookings Institute, April 29, 1935; Melvin, Bruce L. "Emergency" Permanent Legislation Homesteads in American Sociological Review; Ware, Harold and Powell" in Harpers Magazine, April 1935; Glick, Philip "The Federal Subsistence Program" in Yale Law Journal, June 1935, April 29, 1935-Dec. 17, 1936 (Box 3)
  - "Suburban Resettlement"-Appropriations for Suburban Resettlement: Memoranda and program indicating the initial allocation of federal funds to the Resettlement Administration for projects that developed into the Greenbelt towns; copies of memos from Roosevelt, Lee Pressman, Rex Tugwell, Sept. 23, 1935-Nov. 12, 1935 (Box 3)
  - "Suburban Resettlement"-Cincinnati, Greenhills: General Tract plan by Justin Hartzog, 1937, correspondence from Tracy Augur, speeches by Resettlement officials, 1936, 1945-1946, 1963 (Box 24)
  - "Suburban Resettlement"-Greenbelt, Maryland: Announcement by Public Housing Administration of sale of Greenbelt, brochures, 1952 (Box 24)
  - [Suburban Resettlement, Division of Resettlement Admin.] "Statements of Policy SR"- Memoranda, press releases and statements on the non-farm housing projects including the announcement of the establishment of 4 greenbelt towns and Vinton's statement on the program, July 25, 1935-May 12, 1936 (Box 2)
  - "Subsidy Reductions"-Inter-office memoranda, reports, charts on reduction of subsidies to local housing authorities, Edith Wood's comparision with European management; from Nathan Straus, Jacob Crane, Leon Keyserling, Jan. 9, 1940-April 27, 1940 (Box 3)
  - "Summary of Standards and Requirements"-Drafts and revisions of Summary of Standards and Requirements for USHA-Aided Projects, leading to issuance of Summary of June 30, 1940, March 28, 1939-June 3, 1940 (Box 3)
  - "Syracuse"-correspondence, 1944 (Box 1)
  - "'T' Miscellaneous"-correspondence, 1947 (Box 1)
  - "Taft Committee Hearings 1945"
    - FPHA Charts [Federal Public Housing Authority]: Charts and tables on financing, souce of funds, status of F.P.H.A. program, rents, income etc. (TS and MS); statement of Philip Klutznick, Commissioner Federal Public Housing Authority before Senate Subcommittee on Housing and Urban Redevelopment (Taft Committee) (MC), Jan. 1-Feb. 1945 (Box 8)
    - FPHA Testimony and Supplements: Memoranda, lists of witnesses, estimates of costs and write-downs, digest of Philip Klutznick's testimony: inserts for revision of Klutznick's tesmimony; studies and statement for committee record, study on expense items for Defense Homer Corp. in Washington, statements on low-rent housing projects and creation of local authorities, Oct. 1944-April 25, 1945 (Box 8)
    - NHA Testimony: Housing Facts and Goals, charts on statement of Administrator John B. Blandford before Senated Subcommittee on Housing and Urban Redevelopment (Taft Committee) (MC) estimates by Keyserling [?] MS, folder (tabulated) of materials to accompany Blandford's statement, Jan. 5-9, 1945 (Box 8)
    - Other Testimony: Schedule, list of witnesses, letter and statement of Hugh Pomeroy, National Association of Housing Officials, statement of William J. Guste of National Public Housing Conference, report on speech by Senator Taft in Philadelphia, draft of statement by U.S. Conference of Mayors, Jan. 12, 1944-Jan. 13, 1945 (Box 8)
    - Supplemental Material for Taft-1945: Charts on density, site improvement (MS), statement comparing building costs on vacant sites and on slum sites, estimate on cost of acquiring urban slum areas, Feb. 17-April 30, 1945 (Box 8)
    - Taft Committee 1945: Hearings before Senate Special Committee on Post-war economic policy and planning, subcommittee on housing and urban redevelopment (Taft Committee) pt. I 1943 (indexed by Vinton), part 4, 6-15 (1945); House Special Committee Report on postwar economic policy and planning 1945; Senate Committee print on postwar housing 1945; report of Senator O'Mahoney, Oct. 14, 1943-Aug. 1, 1945 (Box 8)
  - "Tax Exemption"-articles and pamphlets on public housing and tax exemption, 1932-1942 (Box 19)
  - "'U' Miscellaneous"-correspondence, 1943 (Box 1)
  - "Unwin, Sir Raymond"-TS notes on Unwin's lecture series at Columbia, Nov. 1936-Jan. 1937; Central Housing Committee reprint of Unwin's Columbia lectures (MC) speech at NAHO conference (TS) 1936, speech on land values 1940 (MC), correspondence from Sir Raymond to Lady Unwin, largely on social matters and housing, Nov. 20, 1937-Dec. 27, 1941, obit. clipping, Itinerary of 1936 housing inspection trip, Nov. 19, 1936-Dec. 27, 1941 (Box 3)
  - "Urban Land Institute"-Proposal for postwar planning, 1941 (Box 1)
  - "Urban Redevelopment" [file heading Cost of Urban Redevelopment Program but filed under Urban]: Report "Urban Redevelopment and Housing" by Guy Green and Alven Hansen 1941 (MC), comments by Leon Keyserling, "Program for Urban Conservation and Development 1942-43" by Charles Archer, notes, memoranda, minutes of conference "Federal Aid for Urban Land Assembly" July 1945, articles, notes and report on Urban Redevelopment Chicago Conference, July 1949 discussion agenda, 1941-1949 (Box 2)
  - "Annals-Sur. of Approaches Housing Problem" [Survey of Approaches to the Housing Problem, Vinton, Warren Jay]: correspondence, draft, printed copies of article written by Vinton for The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science, and mailing list of "those interested", Nov. 23, 1936-Feb. 26, 1937 (Box 2)
  - "War Housing"-correspondence: confidential report on war developments and housing if U.S. should be involved (Oct. 6, 1939) memoranda on defense housing needs, costs, cooperative housing estimates of defense workers' incomes, Oct. 6, 1939-Dec. 11, 1941 (Box 2)
  - "War Housing"-Policy, General: War housing policy intra-office memo, policy draft and article from American City, April 8, 1942-June 1942 (Box 2)
  - "War Housing"-programming-National: Memoranda, charters, drafts and proposed program of war housing i.e. for need arising out of indispensable migration of war workers for fiscal 1943, 1944; 1944 report of Committee on Public Housing of National Institute of Municipal Law Officers (MC) (Box 4)
  - "Wood, Edith Elmer-Memoranda"-Reprint from Shelter Housing in my Time; Reprint from Architectural Record, July 1938 "What Has Kept Costs Down During England's House Building Boom?," memoranda to and from Edith Wood (Consultant, U.S.H.A.) on her experience of British methods, administrative procedure and policies, precise phraseology, relation of shelter rent to income, room sizes, article on defense housing, personal correspondece concerning illness and death of Dr. Wood, 1938-May 14, 1945 (Box 4)
  - [Wurster] "Bauer, Catherine"-correspondence, drafts of speeches and articles on housing and legislation, government programs, National Housing Conference and National Association of Housing Officials, redevelopment, rural houisng in Columbia Basin etc; (file listing Wurster, folder tab Bauer; Cahterine Bauer married William Wurster in 1940), 1937-1949 (Box 4)
- Series III. Chief Economist. Supplimental Office Files, 1945-1949-files not included in the original listing. Listed alphabetically
  - Statements from Creedon, Housing Expediter, Dec. 18, 1946-July 20, 1947 (Box 17)
  - "Community Action Bulletins"-Community Action Bulletin of Veteran's Emergency Housing Program, National Housing Agency; v. 1 #1 (May 1946), 6, 15 (December 1946); v. 2 #2, 8 (May 1947), April 1946-May 1947 (Box 17)
  - "Executive Order Drafts"-Drafts of Executive order consolidating housing agencies and functions of government in war emergency into National Housing Agency, issued Feb. 2, 1942 (TS and MC), organizational chart, Jan. 16-Feb. 24, 1942 (Box 12)
  - "Executive Order Studies"-Memoranda, charts, tables concerning jurisdictions and activitites of government housing agencies pending organizations N.H.A., Fall 1941-FEb. 19, 1942 (Box 12)
  - "Disposition of Housing"-1948-Disposition of War Housing: Transfer of permanent war housing projects for low-rent use, 1947-1948 (Box 13)
  - "Disposition of Permanent War Housing for Low Rent"-Memoranda on policy procedure for transfer of Lanham Act wartime housing projects for low rent use, manual instructions for applications for acquisition of permanent federally-owned housing, policy statement, manual revision, Nov. 15, 1946-Oct. 15, 1947 (Box 7)
  - "Encyclopedia of Housing"-correspondence and drafts concerning Vinton's contribution of article on public housing, Nov. 1947-Oct. 4, 1949 (Box 7)
  - "Housing and Home Finance"-Orders and regulations on reorganization of department, July 31, 1941-Feb. 12, 1948 (Box 7)
  - "Loan and Con. Contract and Res. Current"-[contributions]-agreements and resolution, Nov. 1, 1940-Jan. 6, 1941 (Box 14)
  - "Locality Housing Programs"-Memoranda, charts plans for TDU (Temporary Dwelling Units), drafts of procedure for developing Locality Housing Programs by which National Housing Agency programmed public war housing, Jan.-Nov. 13, 1942 (Box 20)
  - "National Association of Housing Officials"-Journal of Housing: v. 1, #1 (Oct. 1944), #1-12 (1946); v. 4, #1-12 (1947); v. 5, #1, 9-10 (1948); Index 1944-1946, index 1947, 1944-1948 (Box 13)
  - "National Association of Real Estate Boards"-Headlines-1947-48-49 NAREB [National Association of Real Estate Boards]: Newsletter of National Assoc. of Real Estate Boards: v. 14 #2, 7, 11-12, 16-17, 20, 22, 25-26, 31-45 (1947), v. 15 #10, 49 (11948), v. 16 #2, 5, 7, 9, 15-24, 26, 28 (1949), many annotated, 1944-1948 (Box 3)
  - "National Home and Prop. Owners Foundation"-Opposition to Wagner-Ellender-Taft Bill, Aug. 5, 1946-Nov. 2, 1947 (Box 17)
  - "N.H.A. Postwar Discussion Group" [National Housing Agency]-Notes on meetings held by group, especially discussing statement of April 3, 1943 on postwar plans for housing by Coleman Woodbury, Assistant Administrator (Program), N.Y.A., Jan. 15, 1943-Nov. 11, 1943 (Box 17)
  - "N.H.A. Research Committee"-[National Housing Agency]-Memoranda, minutes of meetings on establishment of research and statistics division and its scope of work on postwar problems, July 21-April 12, 1944 (Box 17)
  - "National Industrial Conference Board"-correspondence and report concerning NICB report on Washington slum clearance, 1945 (Box 1)
  - "National Public Housing Conference"-Legislative Newsletter, 1946-47 N.P.H.C.: Legislative Newsletter #1 (Dec. 4, 1945)-2 (Dec. 11, 1945), 4 (Jan. 26, 1946)-6, 10, 12-15, 17-26 (Dec. 5, 1946); #1 (Jan. 25, 1947)-4-13, 15-20-25, 27, 29-32 (Dec. 16, 1947, reporting on federal legislation in the public housing field, 1942, Dec. 4, 1945-June 21, 1947 (Box 2)
  - "National Public Housing Conference"-Legislative Newsletter and News Notes: Legislative Newsletter #1 (Jan. 9, 1948)-3, 5-13, 15 and unnumbered to Nov. 9, 1948; News-Notes, Feb. 15, 1948, March 18, April 22, May 25, 1948, May 26, May 27 and 29, June 1, 3, 5, 7, 8, 10, 14, 15, 17, 21, 23; July 26 and 30, reporting housing legislation in Conress, especially the Taft-Ellender-Wagner Bill, Jan. 9, 1948-Nov. 9, 1948 (Box 2)
  - "President's Message-Reorganization 1946"-Message to Congress transmitting Reorganization Plan #1 of 1946 proposing consolidation of government housing activities under one agency (MC), May 16, 1946 (Box 7)
  - "President's Message-Housing-Feb. 1948"-Letter from Raymond Foley, Administrator (Housing and Home Finance Agency) to President enclosing matter for State of Union address on housing needs and housing legislation, 2 anonymous reports on housing needs, press release of Presidential message calling for continuation of low-rent housing, Nov. 3, 1947-Feb. 23, 1948 (Box 9)
  - "P[ublic] H[ousing] A[dministration] Bulletin"-Bulletin of PHA, Housing and Home Finance Agency, formerly Federal Public Housing Bulletin resuming publication under new title; v. 4 #7, 10-15 (1947-48); v. 5, #1-2, 4-5 (1949) (MC), Oct. 1947-June 1949 (Box 3)
  - "Regional Economists-Memoranda"-Memoranda from Lawrence N. Bloomberg, Assoc. Chief Economist, 1945-1946 (Box 13)
  - "Reorganization Plan no. 3 of 1947"-House of Representatives report, Senate Congressional Record, Senate report, U.S. Senate Committee on Banking and Currency hearings, House concurrent resolution 51 rejecting Plan (Box 10)
  - "Speeches-Foley"-Speech of Raymond Foley, Administrator, Housing and Home Finance Agency, 1947 (Box 18)
  - "Speeches-Myer"-Speeches of Dillon Myer, Commissioner Federal Public Housing Authority (MC), 1946 (Box 18)
  - "Speeches-Wyatt"-Speeches by Wilson Wyatt, National Housing Expediter and Administrator of National Housing Agency (MC), 1946 (Box 18)
  - "Slum Clearance and Urban Redevelopment"-Studies by Vinton leading up to the Title I of Housing Act of 1949, March 1945-March 15, 1949 (Box 19)
  - "State Legislation-Model Bills"-Model drafts of low-rent housing slum clearance and redevelopment laws recommended by National Public Housing Conference, includes model amendment on payments in lieu of taxes, 1945-1946 (Box 7)
  - "Transfer of Housing Projects to War Department"-General order, correspondence, list of projects, 1943-1944 (Box 1)
  - "Urban Redevelopment"-Minutes of Conference on Federal Aid for Urban Land Assembly, July 1945, statements, articles, Chicago Conference on Urban Redevelopment Uly 14-16, 1949 notes, minutes report, discussion agenda, speech dealing with urban redevelopment and slum clearance, Dec. 1944-Nov. 7, 1949 (Box 2)
  - "Veterans Emergency Housing Program"-Reports, releases from Office of Housing Expediter, National Housing Agency, Feb. 7, 1946-June 27, 1947 (Box 17)
  - "Weekly Report to the Administrator"-[Acting] Commissioner F.P.H.A. to administrator [Expediter] National Housing Agency reports #4-56; title varies from report 47 Commissioner Public Housing Authority to Administrator Housing and Home Finance Agency, July 18, 1946-Feb. 18, 1948 (Box 14)
- Series IV. First Assistant Commissioner, Public Housing Authority, file, 1949-1957. Listed Alphabetically
  - [Commitments for Loans and Annual Contributions]-Correspondence, memoranda, policy statements, press releases on loan commitments for funds for local housing authorities, 1951-1953 (Box 1)
  - [Contracts, Preliminary Loans and Annual Contributions]-Preliminary loan contract, Aug. 1956; annual contributions contract pt. I agreement, part II terms and conditions, Dec. 1951, August 1956; report of 1955 Contract Committee and correspondence, 1951-1956 (Box 1)
  - "Current Progress in the Financing of Low-Rent Public Housing 4/18/54"-Report on public housing in 1954, 1955 (Box 16)
  - "Gwinn Amendment"-Correspondence, news releases on Independant Offices Appropriation Act, 1953 (Gwinn Amendment), 1951 (Box 1)
  - [Financing [Bonds]]-Memoranda, clippings, brochures on sale of Housing Authority bonds of local public agencies, Feb. 1952-Oct. 15, 1957 (Box 19)